<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.uscore2.eu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.uscore2.eu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-29T20:01:30+00:00</updated><id>http://www.uscore2.eu/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Uscore2 EU Project</title><subtitle>The Uscore2 project</subtitle><entry><title type="html">International Conference on Risks, Security and Citizenship 2019</title><link href="http://www.uscore2.eu/2019/03/29/international-conference-on-risks-security-and-citizenship-2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="International Conference on Risks, Security and Citizenship 2019" /><published>2019-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.uscore2.eu/2019/03/29/international-conference-on-risks-security-and-citizenship-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.uscore2.eu/2019/03/29/international-conference-on-risks-security-and-citizenship-2019/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/ICRSC_2019_poster_resized_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ICRSC_2019_poster_resized_3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second International Conference on Risks, Security and Citizenship took place on the 28 - 29 of March 2019 in Setúbal, Portugal. The theme of the conference was “Risk Management and Climate Change”. The purpose of the conference was to acknowledge that climate change is now widely recognised as one of the most prominent risks and challenges faced by humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/JP and associate at ICRSC 2019.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Jon Percival and a colleague at ICRSC 2019&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We now find signs the climate is changing. The effects of climate change are several and have repercussions in the social, economic and environmental framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this event, we pretend to reflect on the problematic of risk in the context of the implementation of the Sendai Framework for Disaster Risk Reduction 2015-2030 at the local level, in coherence with the three pillars of the international agenda: International Strategy for Disaster Risk Reduction, Objectives of Sustainable Development and the Action Plan for Climate Action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this thought we develop a thematic multidisciplinary program for knowledge sharing and the application of methodologies regarding the reduction of Disaster Risk, as well has the safeguard of the security of citizens and their communities.” Click &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smpcb.pt/icrsc2019/en/apresentacao.htm&quot; title=&quot;Link to ICRSC 2019 website&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to visit the ICRSC 2019 website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/ICRSC 2019 Programme Crop with white background.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ICRSC 2019 Programme Crop with white background.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On day 1 of the conference the Uscore2 Project Manager, Jon Percival, delivered a presentation on the Uscore2 city-to-city peer review methodology at the Fórum Municipal Luísa Todi. The presentation covered the collaborative approach to the development of the methodology that included international partner cities from Italy, Portugal and the United Kingdom as well as UNISDR, an academic body and government agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/JP_presenting_at_ICRSC_2019.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Jon Percival presenting Uscore2 at ICRSC 2019&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Central to the presentation was the practical application of the methodology which was piloted in Viggiano (Italy), Amadora (Portugal) and Salford (United Kingdom). The lessons learnt from using the methodology in cities with differing scales and risk profiles was instrumental in shaping the development of the Uscore2 approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To view the full International Conference on Risks, Security and Citizenship programme, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://uscore2.eu/downloads/Programme_ICRSC2019.pdf&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Uscore2 Project Round Up 2018 Quarter 4</title><link href="http://www.uscore2.eu/2019/01/04/uscore2-project-round-up-2018-quarter-4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Uscore2 Project Round Up 2018 Quarter 4" /><published>2019-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.uscore2.eu/2019/01/04/uscore2-project-round-up-2018-quarter-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.uscore2.eu/2019/01/04/uscore2-project-round-up-2018-quarter-4/">&lt;p&gt;As the development of the Uscore2 Project neared its final stages during the latter part of 2018, a number of important events took place which represented significant milestones for the advancement and dissemination of the peer review methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;barcelona-resilience-week-barcelona-spain-11-16th-november-2018&quot;&gt;Barcelona Resilience Week, Barcelona, Spain 11-16th November 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/BRW Header.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image credit: http://urbanresiliencehub.org/action/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week-long event, composed of 6 dialogues and numerous workshops, sessions and networking events, brought together 500 participants to develop and foster new working partnerships and collectively face resilience challenges. Barcelona Resilience Week gathered key international actors, together with city representatives, governments, NGOs and innovators to share approaches to addressing urban challenges and implementing the Sustainable Development Goals, New Urban Agenda, Sendai Framework for Disaster Risk Reduction and Paris Agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of BRW was to harness the commitment of initiatives such as the Making Cities Sustainable and Resilient action, the Making Cities Resilient Campaign, city-to-city cooperation programmes and good practices from cities, academia, private sector, and civil society, to scale-up resilience action at the global level. This objective was met and resulted in a growing interest in tools for action such as the City Resilience Profiling Tool and 10 Essentials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Uscore2 Masterclass workshop presented the results of the project and demonstrated the mechanism for an independent and transparent assessment, adding clear value to building local and national resilience. The workshop also emphasised the importance of city-to-city peer learning and sharing of best practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To view the Barcelona Resilience Week programme, please &lt;a href=&quot;https://uscore2.eu/downloads/Programme_Barcelona_Resilience_Week.pdf&quot;&gt;click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;european-forum-for-disaster-risk-reduction-rome-italy-21-23rd-november-2018&quot;&gt;European Forum for Disaster Risk Reduction, Rome, Italy 21-23rd November 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/efdrr-logo-3.1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image credit: https://www.unisdr.org/conference/2018/efdrr&quot; /&gt;
Representatives of European countries, stakeholder groups and partners gathered in Rome, Italy from 21-23rd of November 2018 for the European Forum on Disaster Risk Reduction (EFDRR). The 2018 EFDRR built on the outcomes of the 2017 EFDRR held in Turkey, 2017 Global Platform for Disaster Risk Reduction held in Mexico and aim to address key issues that can accelerate the implementation of the Sendai Framework in coherence with the Sustainable Development Goals and the Paris Agreement. The event represented an opportunity to exchange and move forward on local level resilience, economic risks and reaching the Sendai Framework 2020 priority targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the event members of the Uscore2 team made presentations on the following subjects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peer reviews and the Sendai Framework&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to conduct a peer review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Case studies drawn from project experience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Impact Evaluation Methodology developed as part of the project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learning points gathered throughout the project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;viggiano-amadora-and-salford-peer-review-presentations&quot;&gt;Viggiano, Amadora and Salford Peer Review Presentations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/LC KO Edit 3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the Uscore2 Project pilots of the peer review tool were carried out in each of the Uscore2 partner cities. Following review, the Uscore2 partner city that carried out the peer review formulated a report to capture and consolidate the findings of the activity. During October and December 2018 each of the cities that carried out the review returned to the city they reviewed to present the report and its findings back to stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reports of the peer review findings were presented as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;October 2018 – Salford presented to Viggiano - &lt;a href=&quot;https://uscore2.eu/downloads/Uscore2%20-%20Viggiano%20Peer%20Review%20Feedback%20Report.pdf&quot;&gt;Viggiano Peer Review Feedback Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 2018 – Amadora presented to Salford - &lt;a href=&quot;https://uscore2.eu/downloads/Uscore2%20-%20Greater%20Manchester%20-%20Salford%20-%20Peer%20Review%20Feedback%20Report.pdf&quot;&gt;GM (Salford) Peer Review
Feedback Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 2018 – Viggiano presented to Amadora - &lt;a href=&quot;https://uscore2.eu/downloads/Uscore2%20-%20Amadora%20Peer%20Review%20Feedback%20Report.pdf&quot;&gt;Amadora Peer Review Feedback Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">As the development of the Uscore2 Project neared its final stages during the latter part of 2018, a number of important events took place which represented significant milestones for the advancement and dissemination of the peer review methodology.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">International Organization Standardization Meeting in Stavanger, Norway</title><link href="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/10/11/international-organization-standardization-meeting-in-stavanger-norway/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="International Organization Standardization Meeting in Stavanger, Norway" /><published>2018-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/10/11/international-organization-standardization-meeting-in-stavanger-norway</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/10/11/international-organization-standardization-meeting-in-stavanger-norway/">&lt;p&gt;A working draft of a new international standard on conducting city peer reviews for resilience was discussed over a number of days at meetings held by the International Organization for Standardizations (ISO) in Stavanger Norway, where over 40 countries were represented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard, ISO22392 “Conducting peer reviews for resilience” aims to provide a host of a peer review with the means of assessing their resilience through collaborative efforts. This involves a host inviting a team of independent expert reviewers  to exchange best practice and review progress in order to foster mutual learning and support positive developments in reducing risk and enhancing resilience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ISO22392 was presented to an international delegation of experts in the field of resilience for comment and provided an important opportunity to receive interesting and useful comments on the document. This process will support the publication of the standard, and ultimately assist efforts to promote disaster risk reduction and enhance resilience globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Duncan Shaw, convenor of ISO Technical Committee 292, Working Group 5 ‘Community Resilience’ and project leader for the new ISO22392 led the review of the standard by experts, and was supported by Dr Jennifer Bealt, Research Associate at the University of Manchester. Both Duncan and Jennifer work closely on the UScore2 project, and draw on these experiences to develop ISO22392.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: The UScore2 consortium involves the cities of Salford, Amadora and Viggiano, the University of Manchester, UNISDR, the UK Department of Communities and Local Government, the Portuguese National Authority of Civil Protection and the Associazione di Protezione Civile Gruppo Lucano.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A working draft of a new international standard on conducting city peer reviews for resilience was discussed over a number of days at meetings held by the International Organization for Standardizations (ISO) in Stavanger Norway, where over 40 countries were represented.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Barcelona and Rome Masterclasses</title><link href="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/10/04/barcelona-and-rome-masterclasses/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Barcelona and Rome Masterclasses" /><published>2018-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/10/04/barcelona-and-rome-masterclasses</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/10/04/barcelona-and-rome-masterclasses/">&lt;p&gt;The Uscore2 project will be holding masterclasses at two forthcoming events in Barcelona and Rome. On Tuesday 13th November 2018, the Barcelona Resilience Week (BRW) will be taking place within the Smart City Expo World Congress, which gathers hundreds of city representatives. Similarly, representatives of European countries, stakeholder groups and partners will gather in Rome, 21st to 23rd November 2018, for the European Forum on Disaster Risk Reduction (EFDRR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Uscore2 project has designed and tested a generic, practical, city-to-city, disaster risk reduction peer review tool for cities across EU member states and beyond via the UNISDR Making Cities Resilient campaign (MCR). The project has involved collaborative work between the municipalities of Salford (UK), Amadora (Portugal) and Viggiano (Italy) as well as the University of Manchester (UK), UNISDR, the Ministry of Housing, Communities and Local Government (UK), Portuguese National Authority of Civil Protection and the Associazione di Protezione Civile Gruppo Lucano (Italy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last decade has seen a rising trend in natural and man-made disasters. EU Civil Protection legislation advocates that Member States share best practice and help each other to identify where additional effort is needed to reduce risks. Practical translation of this includes cities conducting better risk assessment and developing action plans. Beyond the EU, the Sendai Framework for Disaster Risk Reduction (DRR) 2015-2030, endorsed by the UN General Assembly in June 2015 established seven global targets including  to “substantially increase the number of countries with national and local DRR strategies by 2020” and emphasizing the need to empower local governments to reduce disaster risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local governments are closest to citizens and communities, playing a vital role in responding to emergencies and delivering essential services which must be resilient to disasters. To respond to calls to prevent and prepare for disasters, municipalities need better access to policies, tools and rigorous, expert critique. Self-assessment tools are available but are often cumbersome to apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peer review of local civil protection mechanisms could offer an independent/ transparent assessment, adding clear value to building local and national resilience. The tool will assist cities with the challenge of strengthening their implementation of disaster risk reduction. Conducting rigorous city-to-city peer reviews is a challenge for practitioners and policy-makers who want to learn from best practice as this has not yet been assembled into an easy to use tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objectives for the city-to-city peer review tool are to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	ensure that the peer review tool reflects a comprehensive, all-of-society approach to DRR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	identify data, information &amp;amp; evidence that is useful when conducting a city-to-city peer review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	aid the implementation of the Sendai Framework at local and therefore national/international levels 		through alignment to local indicators developed in accordance with the Sendai Framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;•	ensure it is useable by cities at all levels of maturity in DRR planning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The peer review tool developed through Uscore2 has piloted in Viggiano, Salford and Amadora. These three cities have different disaster risk profiles; geographical and demographic characteristics; and statutory and regulatory frameworks. All are role models within the Making Cities Resilient Campaign. The effectiveness of the peer review tool has been evaluated using a methodology developed by the University of Manchester. The tool has been aligned to the indicators for the Sendai Framework and UNISDR MCR enabling on-going assessment of its applicability in reporting local progress against the Sendai Framework.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Uscore2 project will be holding masterclasses at two forthcoming events in Barcelona and Rome. On Tuesday 13th November 2018, the Barcelona Resilience Week (BRW) will be taking place within the Smart City Expo World Congress, which gathers hundreds of city representatives. Similarly, representatives of European countries, stakeholder groups and partners will gather in Rome, 21st to 23rd November 2018, for the European Forum on Disaster Risk Reduction (EFDRR).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Uscore2 Final Workshop, Brussels, Belgium</title><link href="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/10/03/uscore2-final-workshop-brussels-belgium/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Uscore2 Final Workshop, Brussels, Belgium" /><published>2018-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/10/03/uscore2-final-workshop-brussels-belgium</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/10/03/uscore2-final-workshop-brussels-belgium/">&lt;p&gt;The Uscore2 project final workshop took place on the 27th and 28th September 2018 in Brussels, Belgium. With the United Nations hosting the event, the international team travelled to the city to work their way through a busy agenda aimed at finalising the city-to-city peer review methodology ahead of dissemination at the Masterclass events in November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/UN Props and Banners.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;UN Props and Banners.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day One&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Objectives of the final workshop were outlined and the team reviewed the project deliverables ahead of Viggiano, Amadora and Salford discussing their experience of being the subject of a peer review under the Uscore2 methodology. The University of Manchester reviewed how the IEM developed and findings from implementing the IEM in the 3 Peer Reviews. The UNISDR and a representative from DG-ECHO reflected on how the experience from the Uscore2 project compares to national level DRR peer reviews and identified recommendations. A table top exercise was also carried out to put under the microscope one of the module that hadn’t been tested as part of the Viggiano, Amadora and Salford peer reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/Kathy Oldham Presenting.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Kathy Oldham Presenting.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day Two&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day Two picked up where Day One left off by continuing with table top exercises on the remaining modules. Discussion centred on the final amendments required by the city-to-city peer review tool and the impact evaluation methodology for DRR. Rounding up Day Two was planning for the Masterclasses that will be held in Barcelona and Rome during the month of November as well as exploration of the final report content.
Following a successful workshop event partners in the project have taken back actions to their respective countries and will forge ahead with completing them ahead of the next series of deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following a successful workshop event partners in the project have taken back actions to their respective countries and will forge ahead with completing them ahead of the next series of deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Uscore2 project final workshop took place on the 27th and 28th September 2018 in Brussels, Belgium. With the United Nations hosting the event, the international team travelled to the city to work their way through a busy agenda aimed at finalising the city-to-city peer review methodology ahead of dissemination at the Masterclass events in November.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Draft ISO22392 a standard on conducting city peer reviews</title><link href="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/10/02/draft-iso22392-a-standard-on-conducting-city-peer-reviews/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Draft ISO22392 a standard on conducting city peer reviews" /><published>2018-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/10/02/draft-iso22392-a-standard-on-conducting-city-peer-reviews</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/10/02/draft-iso22392-a-standard-on-conducting-city-peer-reviews/">&lt;p&gt;A new standard on conducting city peer reviews for disaster risk reduction (DRR) was discussed today at the General Assembly of the International Standards Organisation in Geneva, Switzerland. The standard, ISO22392 “Conducting peer reviews for disaster risk reduction”, will bring together international experiences of conducting peer reviews for DRR across a number of countries to provide guidelines on how cities can benefit, organise and evaluate a peer review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ISO22392 was discussed within a session of how international standards can support global efforts to deliver Sustainable Development Goal 11, Sustainable Cities and Communities. The Sustainable Development Goals are a collection of 17 global goals set by the United Nations General Assembly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Duncan Shaw, moderator of the session and project leader for ISO22392 said “A peer review is a privileged opportunity for a host to reflect on their activities with a team of independent experts. Through conversation, exchanging best practice, and examining performance, mutual learning can be enhanced to identify potential improvements and existing best practices. From this, the host and the reviewers can learn.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The standard will draw on the work of the UScore2 project as well as other international peer reviews to present an easy to use methodology for cities to run a peer review of their own DRR practices.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 800 people attended the ISO General Assembly, representing their national standards bodies, government, NGOs, industry and academia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: The UScore2 consortium involves the cities of Salford, Amadora and Viggiano, the University of Manchester, UNISDR, the UK Department of Communities and Local Government, the Portuguese National Authority of Civil Protection and the Associazione di Protezione Civile Gruppo Lucano.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A new standard on conducting city peer reviews for disaster risk reduction (DRR) was discussed today at the General Assembly of the International Standards Organisation in Geneva, Switzerland. The standard, ISO22392 “Conducting peer reviews for disaster risk reduction”, will bring together international experiences of conducting peer reviews for DRR across a number of countries to provide guidelines on how cities can benefit, organise and evaluate a peer review.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">PreventionWeb: European cities pioneer DRR peer review</title><link href="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/09/28/european-cities-pioneer-drr-peer-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PreventionWeb: European cities pioneer DRR peer review" /><published>2018-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/09/28/european-cities-pioneer-drr-peer-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/09/28/european-cities-pioneer-drr-peer-review/">&lt;p&gt;Source: United Nations Office for Disaster Risk Reduction - Regional Office for Europe (UNISDR EUR)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date: 28 September 2018&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Themes: Disaster Risk Management; Governance; Risk Identification &amp;amp; Assessment; Urban Risk &amp;amp; Planning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.preventionweb.net/english/email/url.php?eid=60925&quot;&gt;http://www.preventionweb.net/english/email/url.php?eid=60925&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Source: United Nations Office for Disaster Risk Reduction - Regional Office for Europe (UNISDR EUR)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Event Summary: Greater Manchester (Salford) Peer Review</title><link href="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/07/16/uscore2-greater-manchester-salford-peer-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Event Summary: Greater Manchester (Salford) Peer Review" /><published>2018-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/07/16/uscore2-greater-manchester-salford-peer-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/07/16/uscore2-greater-manchester-salford-peer-review/">&lt;p&gt;July 9-11th saw Salford welcome the Amadora peer review team to Greater Manchester. The 3 day event brought the panel of Portuguese experts to the city region to review two of the Uscore2 methodology modules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E8a Module - Increase Infrastructure Resilience
E10 Module – Recovery&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 1 of the review brought together representatives of the Greater Manchester Combined Authority (GMCA), Association of Greater Manchester Authorities (AGMA CCRU) Civil Contingencies and Resilience Unit, ARUP, Ministry of Housing Communities and Local Government (MHCLG), Ministry of Defence and KCOM to present on subjects such as Greater Manchester risk and governance, infrastructure resilience, national and civil protection governance and the UK approach to protecting critical infrastructure, military support to protecting infrastructure and telecoms resilience. Following each of the presentations the panel had the opportunity to gain further insight through question and answer sessions. Following the formal sessions the review team visited the offices of Transport for Greater Manchester to discuss transport network resilience and visit the TfGM Control Room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 2 took place at the Highways England Milnrow depot where civil engineering and highways experts presented on the resilience of the strategic road network followed by utility resilience presentations and site visits from Electricity Northwest and United Utilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_9733.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_9733.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 3, the final day, was hosted at The University of Salford’s THINKlab where Councillor Antrobus shared his views on resilience while MHCLG discussed UK national recovery arrangements. AGMA CCRU covered the Greater Manchester approach to recovery while representatives of the GMCA covered the Greater Manchester Resilience Forum. Salford City Council discussed the recovery from the flooding event of 2015 and the Environment Agency covered their approach to post incident recovery which was further enhanced by a guided visit to the second Salford flood basin. The focus group session with the Environment Agency, Urban Vision and Salford City Council covered protective infrastructure and the build back better approach which has been adopted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/IMG_9782.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG_9782.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the conclusion of the peer review the Portuguese review team returned home and will begin to prepare a report for Greater Manchester (Salford) taking into consideration the information that they were presented with during their visit. This will help to build a picture of Greater Manchester’s resilience and the Amadora team will identify areas of good practice and recommendations. With the assistance of The University of Manchester the review team will also carry out an impact evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Uscore2 team are grateful to all participants who attended the event and assisted with its facilitation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">July 9-11th saw Salford welcome the Amadora peer review team to Greater Manchester. The 3 day event brought the panel of Portuguese experts to the city region to review two of the Uscore2 methodology modules:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Date Confirmed: Greater Manchester (Salford) Peer Review</title><link href="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/06/01/greater-manchester-salford-peer-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Date Confirmed: Greater Manchester (Salford) Peer Review" /><published>2018-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/06/01/greater-manchester-salford-peer-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/06/01/greater-manchester-salford-peer-review/">&lt;p&gt;It has now been confirmed that the Uscore2 Greater Manchester (Salford) Peer Review will take place 9th-11th July 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salford will host a peer review team from Amadora, Portugal which will consist of DRR experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The review will be undertaken on the following Uscore2 modules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Module 8a: Increase Infrastructure Resilience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Module 10: Recovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-visit information has been provided to the panel of expert reviewers which will provide them opportunity to study key Greater Manchester resilience documents in advance of the peer review visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Site visits will play a key part of demonstrating the resilience of utility services in the region. Central to the review will be the opportunity to meet local stakeholders who will be presenting information regarding their respective areas of responsibility and provide the opportunity for the panel to ask the stakeholders questions in order to gain an understanding of how resilience plays a key part in Greater Manchester’s structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the review a report will be produced by the Portuguese panel identifying areas of good practice and recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It has now been confirmed that the Uscore2 Greater Manchester (Salford) Peer Review will take place 9th-11th July 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Event Summary: Amadora Peer Review</title><link href="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/04/25/amadora-peer-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Event Summary: Amadora Peer Review" /><published>2018-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/04/25/amadora-peer-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.uscore2.eu/2018/04/25/amadora-peer-review/">&lt;p&gt;The Amadora peer review was held between the 18th and 20th of April 2018. The Portuguese city hosted an international team of experts from Viggiano, Italy who were supported by experts from Salford, United Kingdom to make up the Review Team. Amadora chose to be reviewed on the following modules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Module 1 - Disaster Risk Governance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Module 6 - Strengthen Institutional Capacity for Resilience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the 3-day peer review, members of the Review Team gathered information from sources such as Amadora’s local government, emergency services, community groups and other stakeholders. Prior to the peer review being conducted, information was gathered through an initial exchange of documents as well as presentations, interviews and focus groups during the event itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the peer review, Amadora will be presented with a report highlighting the findings of the peer review. The Review Team from Viggiano are currently in the process of writing this report which will be presented to the Host Team in due course. The Uscore2 methodology will be critiqued once more and go through a further process of refinement ahead of the Salford peer review which will take place before the end of July 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Amadora peer review was held between the 18th and 20th of April 2018. The Portuguese city hosted an international team of experts from Viggiano, Italy who were supported by experts from Salford, United Kingdom to make up the Review Team. Amadora chose to be reviewed on the following modules:</summary></entry></feed>